Sarah Thomas

Wearable Electronics Designer | Pursuing Full Stack Web Development

 $\label{linkedin.com/in/s4r4hthomas | github.com/s4r4htonin | sarahtonindesigns.com s4r4hthomas@gmail.com | 781.631.2546$

SUMMARY

On day one, I'll be able to contribute to your codebase using JavaScript, NodeJS, HTML, and CSS. What I lack in professional experience as a software engineer, I make up for in passion and determination to succeed. As an avid maker and programmer, I strive to meet deadlines with a high standard of quality for all projects that I undertake. My attention to detail is matched by my self motivation, desire to learn, and love of problem solving. I have been learning full stack web development and am eager for the opportunity to join a solid development team, where I can continue to develop and apply my skills.

EDUCATION

Udemy I Online — The Web Developer Bootcamp

CERTIFICATE COMPLETED - JANUARY 2020

Full stack web development course covering vanilla JavaScript, NodeJS, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Express, and MongoDB

Vanderbilt University I Nashville, TN — Bachelor of Arts - Psychology

GRADUATED - DECEMBER 2017

Concentration in Neuroscience & background in Civil Engineering

PROJECTS

RaveReviews — Full Stack Developer

DECEMBER 2019 - FEBRUARY 2020 | MARBLEHEAD, MA

Wrote, tested, and debugged code for a music festival review web application. Built the front and back ends in JavaScript, using a variety of libraries. Implemented user account creation and authentication. Created RESTful API handlers. Managed version control. Deployed web application to obtain feedback from potential users.

Tools/Technologies - JavaScript, NodeJS, Express, RESTful APIs, HTML, CSS, MongoDB, Bootstrap, Git, GitHub, Gitkraken, ejs, Postman, Passport.js, Heroku

SKILLS

Languages:

JavaScript, NodeJS, HTML 5, CSS 3, C++

Tools:

MongoDB, Git, GitHub, Gitkraken, NPM, JSON, Heroku, Amazon AWS, Nginx, Visual Studio Code, Bash, PlatformIO, Arduino, Postman, Fritzing, AutoCAD

Libraries/Frameworks:

Express.js, React, jQuery, Bootstrap 3 & 4

Systems:

macOS, Windows, Ubuntu

Productivity:

Discord, Slack, Trello, Google Suite, Microsoft Office

Other:

Problem Solving, Detail Oriented, Fast Learner, Critical Thinking, Self Starter, Focused, Organization, Time Management, Innovative Design, Research, Project Management, Collaboration, Professionalism, Soldering

Values:

Honesty, Humility, Loyalty, Accountability, Adaptability, Empathy, Open-mindedness

CURRENTLY LEARNING

React

Udemy | The Modern React Bootcamp

HeartRate Reactive LED Music Note — Maker & Programmer

MAY 2019 | MARBLEHEAD, MA

Designed, prototyped, made, and programmed a wearable lighting system. Soldered together hardware and integrated software to produce a wearable product. Connected a heart rate sensor and receiver to create an interactive experience. Successfully delivered a fully functional product by a set deadline.

Tools/Technologies - C++, Arduino, Fritzing

EXPERIENCE

Sarahtonin Designs — Owner — Wearable Electronics Designer

MAY 2014 - PRESENT | MARBLEHEAD, MA

Developed dynamic website for business using JavaScript, NodeJS, and a variety of libraries/frameworks. Built Ubuntu server with Nginx on Amazon (AWS) to host business website. Write and test code for LED designs in C++. Project management from initial research and design to completed wearable product by set deadline. Make patterns and sew clothing by hand, machine, and serger. Prototype and build wearable circuits into outfits using various wires, sensors, and LEDs. Connect hardware via through-hole and surface mount soldering.

Tools/Technologies - JavaScript, NodeJS, Amazon AWS, Express, HTML, CSS, MongoDB, Bootstrap, CSS 3, HTML 5, EC2, Nginx, C++, PlatformIO, Arduino

Marblehead Movers — Office Manager

JULY 2018 - JANUARY 2020 | MARBLEHEAD, MA

Developed an organizational system for the storage facility and implemented methods for tracking customers. Led company to obtain a license for interstate moving. Implemented systems to reach state and federal compliance in order to pass initial safety audit. Organized company by writing an employee handbook and company business plan. Communicated effectively with customers and employees via phone and email. Completed payroll, tracked employee hours, and analyzed company data to discover trends.

Tools/Technologies - Google Suite, Microsoft Office, AutoCAD

CVS Pharmacy — Pharmacy Technician

NOVEMBER 2016 - AUGUST 2017 | SWAMPSCOTT, MA

Prioritized and completed multiple tasks simultaneously while under time constraints. Worked independently while effectively communicating with co-workers and customers. Successfully passed MA state license exam after completing 500 hours in pharmacy. Prepared and filled prescriptions quickly with a high degree of accuracy. Maintained patient confidentiality while resolving order and account issues.

Tools/Technologies - Customer service